CARLOS ALFREDO TORRES CUBILLA



Contact:



Panama City, Panama



+507 6464 1571 +34 663 41 67 71



carlos221296@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/carlos-alfredo-torres-cubilla/



github.com/carlostorrescubila



carlosatc.netlify.app

Languages:

Spanish nativeEnglish advancedGerman beginner

Interests:

- ✓ Outdoor activities
- ✓ Politics
- ✓ Programing
- √ Soccer

About me

I am a friendly, professional and proficient Data Scientist with proven experience in creating Machine Learning algorithms with languages such as R and Python. I have strong technical skills as well as excellent interpersonal skills, allowing me to interact with colleagues from different academic fields. I am looking forward to challenging myself to expand and further improve my computer science skills. My greatest passion in life is to use my technical skills to bring value to my team for the benefit of other people and organizations.

Work experience

January 2021 - Present

Data Scientist at Banco General. Panama City,

- Working holistically with data engineers and other data scientists
- Performing ETL processes
- Producing and developing analytical Machine Learning models with Python
- Visualizing and presenting results of financial analysis

February - April 2020

Data Science Intern at STAT-UP. Munich, Germany

- Structured data in R with the Tidyverse environment
- Analyzed and prepared data from various sources e.g. politics, financial, personal data
- Created interactive HTML reports with R for reporting statistical analysis

September 2018 - January 2019 Statistic Intern at Department of Statistics of the University of Salamanca. Salamanca, Spain

- Instructed students from various fields on how to use statistics in their work
- Assisted teaching and observed best practice

Education

2019 - 2020

MSc in Advanced Analysis of Multivariate Data and Big Data (8.72/10) corresponding 1,3

University of Salamanca, Spain

2016 - 2019

BSc in Statistics (8.14/10) corresponding 1,7

University of Salamanca, Spain

2014 - 2016

BSc in Statistics Engineering (2.47/3)

University of Panama, Panama

2011 - 2013

High School Diploma in Arts, Science and Philosophy

Javier School, Panama City, Panama

Groups and associations

October 2018 -June 2020

Member of DATALAB USAL

- Helped students with the use of data analysis and statistic
- Advanced study in statistics and data analysis
- Joined events and group activities to expand personal and professional skills

Volunteering

April 2018

Volunteer in Startup Olé Accelerator

Awards and Achivements

March 2019

First place in *HackForGood* Salamanca

Computer Skills

Excellent professional knowledge of Python

- ETL process using PySpark
- Statistical methods using SciPy and statsmodels
- Machine learning using Scikit-learn, LightGBM and XGBoost
- Model interpretability with Explainerdashboard and Shapash

Extensive knowledge of R

- Data structures (vectors, matrix, data frames, lists)
- Reading and preprocessing data with Tidyverse
- Descriptive and exploratory analysis using ggplot2
- Web programming using Shiny

Good professional knowledge of Statistical software

- SPSS
- Gretl
- Weka

Experience with BI tools as Power BI and Tableau

Familiar with web design with HTML and CSS